We have gathered here on the occassion of Ram Navami
我們在羅摩 Navamai 的日子 聚集在這裡
everybody has said
每個人都說
Mother please tell us about Shri Ram
母親 請告訴我們有關羅摩的事情
As you know that Shri Rama has taken a very important place in our chakras
你也知道，羅摩在我們的輪穴 佔很重要的位置
He is sitting on our right heart
祂坐在我們的右心輪
Shri Rama has taken a place of a father
羅摩代表父親的位置
so lack of father's duty and love can cause a catch of this chakra
因此，缺乏父親的責任和愛能令 這個輪穴阻塞
In Sahaja Yoga we can understand that Rama and all other gods
在霎哈嘉瑜伽 我們能明白羅摩和其他神祇
came on earth with different power (shakti),
以各種力量降臨地球
they came to do their jobs
祂們肩負任務而來
In the sense Shri Rama has a special job
為此，羅摩有一份特別的任務
Socrates has said benevolent king has to come
就如穌格拉底所說 仁愛厚道的國王要來
For that Shri Rama came
羅摩就是 代表這位仁愛厚道的國王
Shri Rama came in complete human form
祂以人類的形相來
He even forgot that
祂甚至忘記
he is a incarnation of Shri Vishnu He was made to be forgotten
自己是毗濕奴的降世 就是要使祂忘記
But he was Purushottam on earth (perfect human being)
祂是地球上的Purushottam (理想的人類)
you all must have heard of his qualities and his childhood
你們必定有聽過祂的品質 和祂童年的事跡
In Sahaja yoga when we worship any god
在霎哈嘉瑜伽 當我們敬拜任何神祇
what quality we gain from them
我們能從祂們身上取得什麽品質
which qualities we will receive?
我們會吸收到祂們的那種品質
Shri Rama has many
羅摩有很多品質
One that he was ideal another that he is a king
其一是祂是榜樣典範 其二是祂是國王
he kept his people higher than himself
祂視祂的子民比自己更高
than his wife and children
也比祂的妻兒高
If politicians today
若今天的政客
understand this point
能明白這一點
they wouldn't be called selfish
他們就不會被稱呼為自私
they wouldn't be selfish
他們就不會自私
would be follower of Dharma.
亦會是正法的追隨者
Nobody has followed
直至今天
Shri Rama as a role model till today
沒有人追隨或視羅摩為典範榜樣
By singing his bhajans
透過唱祂的拜讚歌
or building an institutions and temples in his name
以祂之名建立機構和建造廟宇
Shri Rama come to you?
羅摩能否來到你身上
Do you get his light in your life?
你有否在你的生命裡 取得祂的光
Only sahaj yogi can bring the light of Shri Rama into the attention
只有霎哈嘉瑜伽士能把羅摩的光 帶進我們的注意力裡
He is totally beyond
祂完全超越
Basically all the deities are free from papas and punyas
基本上，所有神祇都免於 papas(罪孽)和punyas(功德)
so called sins they never sin
所謂的罪孽 祂們從來都是沒有罪
Shri Krishna killed many people
就如克里希納殺死很多人
Shri Rama killed Ravana
羅摩則殺死拉伐那
It can be a sin in worldly sense
這些事情以俗世來看是罪孽
but not in the eyes of god
但神不是這樣看
As they destroy and remove evils they have rights to do anything
因為祂們毀滅邪惡，把壞事物移除 祂們有權做任何事
When Devi slayed Rakshas she has committed a sin?
就如女神殺掉很多惡魔 祂是否犯了罪？
Their work is to destroy the rakshas and protect the saints
祂們的工作 就是毀滅惡魔和保護聖人
In Shri Rama's life Ahilya's saving is the most important
在羅摩的一生 作為 Ahilya的拯救者是最重要的
she was cursed by her husband
她被她的丈夫咀咒
In those times if any women goes out of dharma
那時候，若任何女士偏離正法
and if her husband is high saint he could curse
而她的丈夫又是位處高位的聖人 他就能咀咒人
But Ahillya was blamed falsely
但他卻錯誤地責怪她
And she was made into stone falsely
把她變成石頭
So shri Rama saved Ahilya
羅摩因此拯救Ahilya
Especially his quality to have only one wife
特別的是祂只有一個妻子
his love to one wife must be understood
我們要明白祂只愛一個妻子
Even though he knew Sitaji is Mahalaxmi she herself is a Goddess
即使祂知道悉旦是摩訶拉希什米 的其中一個形相，她是女神
But as a Human he never looked at any other women but his wife
羅摩在人的形相時，除祂的妻子外 祂從不看其他女人
When we talk about Rama we should have the husband pure
當我們談羅摩時 我們就要有這份丈夫的潔淨
To worships shri Rama
要敬拜羅摩
Women should have the same faith in husbands as Sitaji used to
女人要對她的丈夫如悉旦對她的 丈夫那樣，有同樣的信任
Husbands also need the quality of Shri Ram who believed one wife
同樣，丈夫也要像羅摩 只能有一個妻子
Not difficult for sahaja yogis
對霎哈嘉瑜伽士來說，不難做到
Women should be respected Have respect for wifes
女人要受到尊重 對妻子要尊重
When Ravana kidnapped Sitaji
當拉伐那綁架悉旦
Shri Rama felt his duty to rescue her
羅摩感到有責任拯救她
But in his kingdom he was so just that
但對祂的子民來說
For people he left her after spending so many years to rescue
For people he left her 祂要離開多年來拯救她
As Sitaji herself a Devi so there's no effect
悉旦也是女神，離開她 不會有任何嚴重的後果
So Shri Rama did it
羅摩因此離開她
to keep the benevolence of public opinion
為了大眾的福祉
that society wouln't accpect the women
不然社會不會接受
who are questioned.
受質疑的女人
Although she is a Devi Pure and Nirmala
雖然她是女神 純潔和 Nirmala
Later that Sita also left him somehow
之後，不知何故，悉旦也離開祂
She left him as a woman and Shri Rama as a man
她就如女人般離開祂 羅摩亦如男人般離開她
Sitaji disappeared into the mother earth and Shri Rama went into River Sarayu
悉旦消失在大地之母裡 而羅摩則跳進 Sarayu河
Their life is very eventful and full of Miracles
祂們的一生多姿多彩，充滿奇蹟
You see how shri Sita and Rama have good attitude and are faithful each other
你看到祂們對待對方的態度 互相忠誠
Even if she was left Sita thought it her duty
即使她離開 悉旦認為這是她的責任
She never complained or talked ill of him
她從不投訴羅摩，或說祂壞話
And effortlessly she has raised her children
她毫不費力的從容地 養育她的孩子
Shri Rama's children are called Luv and Kush
羅摩的孩子名為Luv 和Kush
They came as devotees and we can see them as disciples
他們以虔敬者來到這個世界 我們能視他們為門徒
They represents Shisya (disciples)
他們代表 Shisya (門徒)和
the power of Shisya so we can be disciple of someone
門徒的力量 因此我們能成為某人的門徒
As disciples they learned archery when they were small
作為門徒 他們在很年幼時已經學習射箭
And learned Ramayana and got proficiency in the music
學習羅摩衍那，對音樂很熟練
Showing the disciples must surrender completely to the Guru
這顯示門徒必須完全順服委身於 他們的導師
We also have a disciples in us
我們內在亦有門徒
They were  completely surrendered to the Mother who is Shakti
他們完全順服於母親，她是力量
Even they were about to fight against Shri Rama
他們還準備就諸 為母親與羅摩一起戰鬥
they kept Mother highest in the world
他們視母親為全世界最偉大的
The mother cared them and made them completely dharmic
母親養育他們，照顧他們 令他們堅守正法
It was her first duty
這是她首要責任
Not like today wives just cry "my husband left me"
不像今天的妻子 只會日夜都在哭我的丈夫離開我
But with husband they fight always and if he leaves they will cry
但當丈夫回來，她們就會與他 時刻爭吵，一旦他離開，她們就哭
He has left no problem I have children, I will care for them
若他離開，沒問題，我有孩子 我要照顧他們
they will get all they need
孩子會得到他們一切所需
Sitaj's life was special with bravery and strength
悉旦的人生很特別 充滿勇氣和毅力
Every woman must have it
每個女人都要有 這份勇氣和毅力
Even if you are separated with your husband or far away
即使你與丈夫分開，或他遠離你
there shouldn't be any loss or shortage for children
這應不會有任何損失 對孩子亦沒有任何缺失
Because her duty is the most important thing
因為她對孩子的責任 是最重要的
We shouldn't give up most important thing
我們不應放棄最重要的事情
In sahaja yoga all women should get this power
在霎哈嘉瑜伽 所有女人都要取得這力量
Shri Rama's life was very pure and Nirmal
羅摩的人生是很純潔和 Nirmal
he gave up everything for his wife
祂為妻子放棄一切
His wife had gone, he had to live alone and he had to leave her
祂的妻子走了，祂要獨自生活 祂必須離開她
He gave up all the comforts of the life
祂放棄生活上的一切舒適
You know he used to sleep on grass, on floor and walked barefeet
你也知道，祂常常睡在草地上 睡在地上，赤腳行走
and wear clothes like saints
也常常穿得像聖人
All these are not stories it's a fact
所有這些都不是故事，是事實
In India many people used to have high standard life
在印度 很多人過著很高標準的生活
and they have never thought about small and low level things
他們從未想過微小低層次的事物
But all these ideals of our country have beccome fake
但我們國家，這些典範 卻已經變得虛假
By singing bhajans to Ram we think we are done
透過向羅摩唱拜讚歌 我們以為自己已經做到
we have got a kind of hypocracy
這是一種偽善
In countries without these ideals
沒有這些典範的國家
people try to become the ideals correcting themselves
人們嘗試想成為典範 他們改正自己
If you have the ideal in front of us
若你們有典範榜樣在前
you don't  become Shri Rama or Krishna
我們不能成為羅摩或克里希納
or you have anything to do with them
或與祂們有任何關係
We feel like that
我們有這種感受
But if we have Shri Rama inside his light can be in our attention
若我們內在有羅摩 祂的光可以在我們注意力裡
Let's understand
讓我們理解
the circumstances when Shri Rama came on earth
羅摩在什麽情況下 降臨這個地球
Sahaja Yogi must understand
霎哈嘉瑜伽士必須明白
If we get Shri Rama's state All our political problems will go
若我們能取得羅摩的狀態 我們所有政治問題都會消失
when we decide to become like shri Rama
當我們決定變得像羅摩
Then everyone becomes good
那麽每個人都變成好人
firstly dharma, success and education then the ideals
他們先得到正法，取得成功 受到教育，成為典範
for that he made his life very idealistic
為此，祂令自己的人生很理想
When someone tells you something but he doesn't do it himself
當某人對你說了一些 他們也做不到的事情
Then how can you trust him and get his quality
你會否相信他並以他為榜樣
There are many people who say we believe in this and that
很多人說 我相信這樣，相信那樣
But they are opposite
他們卻有相反的言行
Followers of Ram seems to be the biggest fraud politician and they have many wives, impossible
羅摩的追隨者看來是 最大的騙子政客 他們有很多妻子，沒可能是這樣的
What is the duty of Sahaja Yogis' life?
因此 霎哈嘉瑜伽士有什麽是責任
we have to bring the light of god in our attention
我們要把神的光 帶進我們的注意力
We must see and behave as Shri Rama
我們必須以羅摩的角度看事物 言行舉止亦要像祂
What would Shri Rama or Sita do in this situation
若這種事情發生 羅摩和悉旦會怎樣做
What would Sita ji say?
悉旦會說什麽
How would Sita behave? She is also Gruhlaxmi
她會有怎樣的言行 她也是古哈拉希什米
As you know Sitaji took many births
你也知道，悉旦多次降世
Gruhlaxmi was in the form of Fatima-bi
這些古哈拉希什米的降世中 有法蒂瑪的形相
She was humbly in the house but all dharma was done by her power
她謙卑的在家裡，但所有正法的 工作都是以她的力量來做的
Not necessary for her to go out and give big lectures
她不需要外出，作重大的演說
You can do that work at home with children relatives and friends
你能在家裡，與孩子 親人和朋友做這工作
you can spread sahaja Yoga at the house
你可以在家裡傳揚霎哈嘉瑜伽
After getting all of it you can go out to society
在擁有力量之後 你可以進入社區
But ladies have to have purity like Sitaji first
但首先，女士要有悉旦的純潔
First thing of the purity is motherhood and love
純真首先是母性和愛
When she was in exile never complained that my husband doesn't earn
當她與丈夫被流放到森林裡 她從不投訴︰我的丈夫沒有賺錢
He doesn't do this he doesn't buy this and that
他沒有這樣做 他沒有買這東西，那東西
If he is in jungle so I am What he will eat I wil
若他留在森林，我也要留在森林 他吃什麽，我也吃什麽
I don't eat before him I serve him first
我不會在他面前吃 我會伺候他先吃
and  brother in law then I will eat
也會伺候我丈夫的兄弟 之後我才吃
Nowadays women think there is much pressure of the work But it is not
現在女人以為這種工作 給她們壓力，但不是這樣
A woman is like earth element she can absorb
女人就像土元素 她能吸收
So many are given by the earth
大地給予我們一切
In the same way women are like the earth
同樣，女人亦要像大地
We have got so many powers that we can take everything inside
我們擁有很多力量 我們內在能包容一切
and shower the rain of love God has given us the power
亦能灑下愛之雨 神賜予我們力量
For example this fan is moving Which one is greater, the power or fan?
例如，風扇在移動 電力還是風扇比較了不起
If you think fan is greater as  it's moving Then it's wrong
若你認為因為風扇在動 所以它更了不起，你錯了
Women are ocean of shakti
女人是力量的海洋
With that support Men does their work
得到她的支持 男人才能做好他的工作
They are potential and kinetic Women are potential and men are kinetic
有種說法是潛在和動力 潛在的是女人，男人則是動力
But if you start running like them
若你開始像他們那樣跑
It's not good No need for women
就不大好 女人沒必要這樣
Each one is unique but equally important But women can be good for both
男女各有獨特之處，亦同樣重要 女人兩者都能做好
When the time comes women can be more productive
當時候到了 女人可以更有生產力
In Maharashtra there was a 17-year-old widow named Tarabai
在馬哈拉斯特拉邦 有個名為Tarabai的十七歲寡婦
She was the daughter-in-law of Shivaji
她是悉旦(Shivaji)的媳婦
Only she could defeat Aurangzeb
只有她打敗過Aurangzeb
Her grave was built
她的墳墓建在Aurangabaad
You must understand women can keep all her power within her to become ferocious
你必須明白 女人把所有力量保存在內 她就變得勇猛
But  if she waste her powers in fighting, arguing, complaining or in frivolous things
但若她把她的力量浪費在 爭鬥上，爭辯上，投訴上 或細微瑣碎的事情上
then her power would be gone
那麽她的力量就會消失
Women are so powerful that she can work more than men if she want
女人是那麽有力量，若她想 她能比男人做得更多
But first of all she must respect her powers
但首先，她要尊重自己的力量
by scattering and wasting she becomes powerless
若她分散和浪費自己的力量 她真的變得毫無力量
this kind of woman is not good
這種女人不好
Women's job is very important and full of dignity
女人的工作是很重要的 充滿尊貴
Women should be very modest and very wise
女人要很溫和，很有智慧
Let Men use bad words but women cannot
讓男人說壞話吧，女人不能說
Men can argue and would fight let them do but not Women
男人會爭辯，亦會打架 讓他們這樣吧，但女人不能
Their job is to make peace, protection and helping people
她們的工作是製造和平 保護人，幫助人
She is like shield not like sword and sword cannot be shield
她像盾牌，不是像劍 劍不能是盾牌
Shield is greater than sword as shield can bear the sword
盾牌比劍更了不起 因為盾牌能抵抗劍的攻擊
Sword can be broken but not shield
劍會折斷但盾牌不會
So her most important power is humility
所以她最重要的力量是謙卑
With humility comes all the powers
透過謙卑，所有力量都會來
It's not difficult for sahaj yogis not at all
對霎哈嘉瑜伽士這不困難 完全不困難
I see many sahaja yoginis chat a lot
我看到很多女霎哈嘉瑜伽士 閒聊太多
anywhere they will chat with men
在任何地方 她們都能與男人閒聊
"Mother help me" "what happened"
「母親，請幫我。」「什麽事？」
"The lady talks a lot please help me"
「這個女人說話大多，請幫我。」
"I am tired of her"
「我對她很厭倦。」
There isn't much to talk with men What's the need?
沒有太多事情可以和男人談 有什麽需要說些無聊話
Among women also
即使女人之間亦不用說太多話
In sahaja yoga men study more
在霎哈嘉瑜伽，男人更要學習
About Sahaja Yoga and the chakras
什麽是霎哈嘉瑜伽？什麽是輪穴
Which chakra is driving people and is catching?
什麽輪穴在驅動人 什麽輪穴有阻塞
Man knows all women would be left behind
男人懂所有知識 女人便會落後
Women must learn
女人也要學習這些知識
For men Shri Rama is our ideal
就男人而言，羅摩是我們的典範
In this sense Muslims are amazing
就此穆斯林真的令人很驚訝
I don't want to say bad things
我不想說壞話
Say if you go to Riyad no  Muslim will see you
例如，若你到 Ryaad 沒一個穆斯林會看你
they will respect women If women are crossing the street
他們非常尊重婦女 若有女人要過馬路
they will stop the car respecting women
他們會把車子停下來 那裡尊重婦女
But here it's opposite I don't know why
我不知道為何這裡的人對婦女 有相反的態度
we see women with some intention
我們看女人是有企圖的
Seeing every woman they will break the neck
即使他們的頸子折斷 也會不停的看
It's a big sin to see every woman
這樣看女人是很大的罪孽
In sahaja yoga it's prohibited completely
在霎哈嘉瑜伽是禁止這樣做 完全禁止這樣做
Firstly you will spoil your eyes and Sahaja Yoga
首先，這樣做你會破壞 你的眼睛和霎哈嘉瑜伽
Otherwise you may become blind
不然，或許你們會盲眼
Sometimes I see people have wandering eyes
有時 我看到人們有搖擺不定的眼神
While talking eyes are wandering women too
在說話時，眼神搖擺不定 女人也一樣
The biggest loss is your attention
最大的損失是你的注意力
Your attention goes here and there
你的注意力四處放
then what's the use of self-realization
那麽，有自覺又有何用
Without concentration Chitta can't be active
若你的注意力不集中 就不能起作用
Concentration must be obtained
注意力必須集中
In the west the disease is more common among men
在西方 這種疾病在男人間很普遍
Western yogis are not alike They know it's bad
西方的霎哈嘉瑜伽士並不相似 他們知道這是很壞的
They asked me the solution
他們問我有什麽解決辦法
Look at only ground and up to 3 feets you don't have to see above
你們只要看著地面，直到三呎 不看三呎以上
Look at the ground Yogis are walking looking at the ground abroad
看著地面 瑜伽士走路時看著地面
You see all good things, flowers and children Nothing to see above
就能看到好東西，看到花朵 孩子上面沒什麽好看
So, that's how you should control your chitta
你就是這樣控制你的注意力
Shri Rama didn't need it If you have a respect to shri Rama
羅摩不需要這樣 若你尊重羅摩
You must control your chitta like him
就必須像祂那樣控制你的注意力
Tell your wife you respect her as shakti But she has to deserve it
告訴你的妻子，你尊重她作為力量 但她要值得受尊重
"Yatr naryan pujante tatr ramante devata"
Yatr naryan pujante tatr ramante devata
"Where women are respected resides god" But they have to be respectable
即那裡的婦女受到尊重 那裡就有神 但她們要值得受尊重
Please sit down
請坐下
Don't move during Puja
崇拜時不要四處走
If the woman is worshipable "Pujyante" means "worshipable"
若女人值得受敬拜 "Pujyante" 意思是值得受敬拜
Who like to worship a bad woman cruel Rakshasi?
誰會喜歡敬拜壞女人 殘忍的惡魔
Those who are worshpable should be worshipped There resides gods
我們要敬拜值得受敬拜的人 那裡有神在
Firstly they are mothers of children
首先，她們是孩子的母親
If husband scolds wife in front of children
若丈夫在孩子面前諷刺他的妻子
then children will never respect mother
孩子就不會尊重他們的母親
It's prime minister and deputy minister
這是總理或副總理
Women shouldn't insult her husband too
女人也不應侮辱她的丈夫
Power goes to children from father
力量是父親給孩子的
Without this basic understanding they fight to take control
沒有這基本的理解 他們會因為想掌事而打架
If woman knows handling of man there won't be any fights
若女人知道怎樣應對男人 就不會有任何爭吵
Handling men is very easy as they are just like children
應付男人很容易 因為男人就像孩子
they are innocent like children
他們純真如孩子
By talking nonsense you can't handle them
向他們說些荒唐的說話 你是不能應付他們
You must forgive them as children
你要像原諒孩子般原諒他們
If they fight outside they get troubled
若他們在外面與別人爭吵 他們會有麻煩
They can get angry only to wife
他們只能生妻子氣
Getting angry at home is OK
在家裡生氣還可以
Until you get this feeling, you cannot have mutual understanding, love and joy
除非你有這種感覺 不然你們是不能互相了解體諒 相親相愛和有喜樂
Men also should care for wife's needs
男人亦要關心妻子的需要
if wife is wrong, husband has duty to say no "It's wrong, I won't do this"
若妻子錯了，丈夫有責任說不 這是錯的，我不會這樣做
But no need to fight on small things It doesn't look good as sahaja yogis
沒必要為一些瑣事爭吵 這樣對霎哈嘉瑜伽士來說不大好看
I am surprised that Sahaja couples fight each other
我很驚訝，霎哈嘉瑜伽的夫婦爭吵
They come to complain about each other
他們投訴對方
How come sahaja couple cannot be together peacefully while I'm talking about peace to the whole world
為何霎哈嘉瑜伽的夫婦 不能和平共處 而我卻對全世界說和平
It won't work out if you are fighting like that
若你們像這樣爭吵 那是不能成事的
Husband has to have complete understanding of his wife first
首先，丈夫要完全理解體諒妻子
And know that all the other women are like your sisters and mothers
亦要知道全世界的其他女人 等同是你的姊妹和母親
If someone is not clean even after Sahaja Yoga then there's no way out
即使來霎哈嘉瑜伽後 若人的狀況不清潔 就是沒有出路
There was a swiss man not a Sahaja Yogi
有個瑞士男人 他不是霎哈嘉瑜伽士
Not Indian He was a father of a Sahaja Yogini
不是印度人 他是一個霎哈嘉女瑜伽士的父親
Girl's husband had wandering eyes but came to sahaja yoga
女孩的丈夫有搖擺不定的眼睛 即使他已來霎哈嘉瑜伽
They both came to Sahaja Yoga The girl is very good but he went on doing it
他們兩人都來了霎哈嘉瑜伽 女孩很好，但他仍繼續這樣
The non-yogi father told her to leave him
那個不是瑜伽士的父親 告訴她離開他
"Even after sahaja yoga if he can't be cleansed then leave him"
即使來霎哈嘉瑜伽後 若他仍不清潔，離開他吧
"He is not a Sahaja Yogi don't relate with him"
他不是霎哈嘉瑜伽士 不要與他有任何關連
Even Non-Sahaja Yogi can understand that the person can't be cleansed
即使不是霎哈嘉瑜伽士也能明白 這個人不能得到潔淨
He doesn't have stable attention then it is bad
他沒有穩定的注意力 這很壞
Our culture is that men and women must be brother and sister
我們的文化是男女的關係必須是 兄弟姊妹的關係
But I see a talkative woman just go to talk to men
但我看到一個健談的女人 她只與男人交談
I don't understand it They don't sit with other ladies but with men
我就是不明白，她們不與其他女士 一起坐，只與男人一起坐
Same with men just start chatting with women
男人也一樣，只與女人聊天
Even with maid or anyone just start talking, no self-esteem
即使那個女人是女僕還是任何女人 開始說話，完全沒有自尊
We think it's masculinity but Shri Rama is the perfect man who is highest
我們以為這是男子氣概 羅摩是最高最完美的男人
But the one at the bottom think they are perfect
在底層的人卻以為自己是完美的
Where is perfection? Not believing in Shri Rama but in devil
什麽是完美 不相信羅摩，只相信邪魔
If you believe in Shri Rama follow his ideal
若你相信羅摩，就必須以祂為榜樣
Therefore children and women are getting spoiled
因此，孩子被寵壞，女人也被寵壞
But still Indian women maintained good culture here
但這裡的印度女人 仍能保持良好的印度文化
If they were like Americans what it would have been Men are fixed in terrible condition there
若她們像美國人，情況會是怎麽樣 那裡的男人境況很可怕
After 2-3 marriages Men becomes bunkrupt but women make a palace
在結兩三次婚後，男人破產 女人卻能建一所皇宮
It's bad in America Children are running away from home
在美國，情況很差 孩子離家出走
Indian woman manage their house husband and children
印度的婦女好好管理她們的房子 管理丈夫和孩子
But it's changing They think the same like husbands
但這些事情在轉變 她們的想法與丈夫一樣
If he runs away with 10 women then we go with 15 men
若他與十個女人私奔 我就和十五個男人私奔
If he is going to hell then I go before him
若他要進地獄，我比他先進地獄
Women shouldn't do it The base of dharma is in woman's hand
女人不應這樣做 正法的根基在女人手上
Woman must manage husband dharmic making him understand
女人必須好好管理丈夫的正法 亦要令他明白
This is the biggest duty and power of woman to be Dharmaic
這是女人最大的責任和力量 就是要合乎正道
Biggest dharma is forgiveness Without it nothing works out
正法中最重要的正法是寛恕 沒有寛恕，什麽也成就不了
First thing she must have forgiveness Forgive children, husband
首先，她要有寛恕 寛恕孩子，寛恕丈夫
give refuge to house servants all are her duty
給予僕人庇護 這些全是女人的責任
This is the work that Shri Rama couldn't do neither Shri Krishna nor Shri Jesus
這些工作羅摩做不了 克里希納和耶穌基督也做不了
Rama would have killed everyone who is useless, adharmic and flirt
羅摩會殺死沒用的，反正法的 污穢不堪的人
Don't know how many he would be finished
我們不知道 祂還要令多少人完蛋
Krishna would use his sudarshan chakra and there would be a battle
克里希納會運用祂的sudarshan輪穴 那會有一場戰爭
Christ would crucify himself
基督會釘自己上十字架
One crucifiction is better than everyday
只釘上十字架一次 比每天都要釘上十字架好
Only Mother can do this work With such a power of love
只有母親能這樣做 以愛的力量
Anything can be worked out with her power of love
一切都能以她愛的力量來成就
She holds everything with so much love that children don't mind correcting
她以愛包容一切 因此，她的孩子不介意改正
For instance when trouble comes only mother knows how to handle it and scold later
例如，若有什麽麻煩事發生 只有母親知道怎樣處理 她遲一點才去責駡
Because children understands mother's love and it is for them
因為孩子知道母親愛他們 她做什麽都是為他們好
With father children may react but not with mother's love without expectation
孩子或許會對父親有反應 但不會對母親 母親的愛是不期望任何回報
She doesn't want anything but her children to be good and get all my powers, all good in me
她什麽也不要，只要她的孩子妥當 取得她所有的力量，她的所有優點
If mother feels it children will be fine
若母親有這種想法，孩子就會妥當
But some mothers are very interfering and get involved in everything
但有些母親是很煩擾 她們干涉一切，染指一切
She comes always in front while husband is at the back
她常常站在前面 丈夫只能在後面
Children will be spoiled by it
若這樣，孩子會被寵壞
Under such harmful environment children can be very emotional
在這種富傷害性的環境下 孩子可以很情緒化
So woman should be behind and make her husband in front
所以女人要站在後面 讓她們的丈夫站在前面
Whatever husbands do wifes must help him behind
不管丈夫做什麽 妻子都要在後面幫助他
The source of his power is wife Then how pure and hard-working she should be
他的力量源自妻子 妻子應是純潔和勤勉的
I put everything on woman because I know you have great powers inside
我把一切都交給女人 因為我知道你們內在很有力量
Look at me as a Mother I must make everyone saints
看看我作為母親 我要令每個人都成為聖人
Curing many diseases to make people saints
要治好很多疾病 令人成為聖人
Did anyone do this job? Only Ahilya was saved
還有誰在做著這些工作？ 只有Ahilya獲得拯救
Jesus saved 21 people
耶穌拯救了二十一人
I must have saved 21000 now
到目前為此 我應拯救了二萬一千人
Going around the world to do everyone's job
周遊列國，做每個人的工作
it's still going on but I don't feel because of love
這種情況仍然持續，因為愛的力量 我不感到怎樣
Maybe I should put bandhan as I don't know what kind of people I meet
或許出門前要做班丹 因為我不知道我會遇到什麽人
But as soon as people comes to me I absorb all the problems
但一旦任何人來找我 我立即吸收了他們所有的問題
So love acts by itself I know everything is done by love
所以愛自動起作用 我知道是愛成就一切
I don't feel bad whatever happens Only Mother can bear the pain
不管什麽發生，我沒有壞感覺 只有母親能承受這份痛苦
So I want you to grow consistantly without hurdles
我想你們能沒有障礙的穩步成長
Also men should help their wives fully Understand and respect them
男人要全力幫助他們的妻子 體諒她們，尊重她們
Until the 2 wheels gets balanced the chariot doesn't go forward
除非戰車的兩個車輪能夠平衡 不然它不會往前走
They both should be the same but one on the left and the other on the right
他們兩人要一樣 一個在左，一個在右
It won't work if you change it
若你改變他們的位置 就不合適了
It is moving and working because they are the same but unique
這兩種車輪在運作，在工作 因為它們是相同又是不同
Same in the sense of height length and width but they work differently
相同在於高度、長度、闊度 但它們負責的工作卻不同
It's the same in our life
同樣情況發生在我們的生命裡
Shri Rama didn't think only about husband and wife
所以羅摩不單只想著丈夫和妻子
Didn't think only about children and family
亦不單想著孩子和家庭
Also of brother, sister, mother, father and everyone as a normal human being
祂還想著兄弟、姊妹、母親、父親 每一個人，就如正常的人類一樣
After he thought about society
之後，他才想及社會
About public, state and country
想及大眾，也想及國家
As a human being he has shown human ideals in his activities
作為人類，祂透過活動 顯示人類的典範該是怎麽樣
The person who loved his wife so much knew she was pure and hed left her
很愛妻子的人知道妻子是純潔的 他離開她
Now people give so much to their own wife but they never give to poor people
現在，他們給妻子很多東西 卻從不施予窮人什麽
Otherwise they give to their relatives It's a disease among politicians
不然，亦會把錢給親人 這是政客的一種病
But the one who has wife who is sakshat devi had to leave her
妻子是sakshat devi的人 就要離開她
We must understand it's attachment to relatives and possessions
我們要明白，這是種執著依戀 依戀我們的親人和財產
In west marriage relation wasn't alright but after Sahaja Yoga wife became everything
西方國家的婚姻關係不怎樣妥當 在來霎哈嘉瑜伽後，妻子變成一切
Here leaders had to leave because their wives were not alright
這裡的領袖要離開 因為他們的妻子不妥當
Their attention got spoiled by wife's preaching
透過妻子的鼓吹 他們的注意力受到破壞
At least five yogi left because of their wives
至少五個瑜伽士 因為他們的妻子而離開
Wives should understand Sahaja Yoga and their role in it
妻子必須明白霎哈嘉瑜伽和 他們在霎哈嘉瑜伽的角色
In this case husbands shouldn't agree with their wives at all
這種情況下，丈夫完全不應 同意他們的妻子
Tell her that “You talk and move too much, Be quiet"
要告訴她︰「你說太多話 走得太多，請安靜。」
You are useless Your chakras are not alright
你一無事處，你的輪穴亦不妥當
She will be alright only in this way
只有這樣，她才會妥當
But instead you blame yourself and obey your wife?
但取而代之，你卻責怪自己 仍遵從你的妻子？
If she tells you to steal, you do it?
若她要你去偷竊，你會去嗎？
Even after Sahaja Yoga you still have some catches to take care
即使來霎哈嘉瑜伽後 你仍有些阻塞要處理
On the occasion of Shri Rama Hanuman should be remembered as his great devotee
今天在羅摩的慶典，我們要記著 哈奴曼作為羅摩偉大的虔敬者
And how he was busy at his service
哈奴曼是如何忙於事奉
He was aware that his life is for serving Shri Rama
祂知道自己的生命是為伺候羅摩
We should have his awereness in Sahaj Yoga
我們亦要對霎哈嘉瑜伽 採取同樣的態度
But it doesn't mean you cook food for me which I don't eat
這不是說 你要為我煮我不吃的食物
You trouble me cooking so much this and that
你煮太多食物令我感到煩擾
Don't keep on serving someone forcefully
不要強迫人接受你的伺候
What we need is zeal to serve (Sewa)
我們要熱心的去伺奉
Hanuman didn't serve food to Shri Rama
哈奴曼沒有向羅摩端上食物
Delhi people kept on serving food so much
德里人透過烹調很多食物 令我感到煩擾
that I had to tell them I wouln't come if you don't stop
我因此要告訴他們，若你不停止 向我端上煮食物，我就不來
Do what you have to do
做你要做的事情
It's bad to force someone to eat
強迫人吃是很差勁的
serving one after another
有些人不停的端上食物
I don't need anything and I am tired
我什麽也不需要 我對這種情況已感到很厭倦
I told you only flowers But don't spend too much also
我告訴你，只帶些花朵來就行 但不要花太多錢來買花
A lot of flowers make me worry sometimes
有時太多花亦令我擔憂
Please your Mother in balance She is a simple woman who don't understand these
以平衡的方式取悅你的母親 她是個簡單的女人 她不會明白這些
We have to learn that zeal to serve is from Hanuman ji
我們必須向哈奴曼 學習那份熱情去侍奉
There is no special service for me
不用對我有特別的服務
But if you want to serve me serve to Sahaj Yoga
若你想服務我 就服務霎哈嘉瑜伽吧
Serving to Sahaja Yoga is serving to me
服務霎哈嘉瑜伽就是服務我
How many realisation have you given
你給了多少人自覺
How many did you transform and inspire
轉化和啟發了多少人
But if you say to new people they have bhoot, they just leave
若你對新來的人說︰ 你有亡靈附著，他們會離開
One gentleman was told he has 3 bhoots in him so he left Sahaja Yoga
有人告訴這個男士 他有三個亡靈附著他 因此他離開了
he was told number of bhoots even
甚至有多少個亡靈也告訴他
he believed it because the Yogi was an authority in the local area
他相信因為告訴他的瑜伽士 是這地方有權勢的大人物
I don't know who but the person left
我不知道這個大人物是誰 但這個人已經走了
So what we have to learn from Hanuman is the zeal
我們要向哈奴曼 學習什麽是熱切渴望
" Ram kaj karne ko tatpar" (eager to do Ram's work)
(渴望為羅摩辦事)
What is our work? My work is sahaj yoga
什麽是我們的工作 我的工作是霎哈嘉瑜伽
To raise kundalini
提昇靈量
To make people peaceful and lovable talking about love
令人平和，有愛心，談愛
Talk about Sahaja Yoga, about chakras Make them understand
對他們談霎哈嘉瑜伽，談輪穴 令他們明白
Doesn't mean you start giving lecture Some people started to give so much lecture
這不是說你要開始演講 有些人演講太多
I had to tell them to stop Otherwise Sahaja Yoga will be finished
我要告訴他們停止演講 不然霎哈嘉瑜伽會完蛋
Only long lectures No time for Mother's talk and Aarti
說一個很長的講話 卻沒時間聽母親的講話和做搖燈禮
He said he just can't stop
他說他就是停不了
He doesn't know why "How can I fix it?"
他不知道為何會這樣 我怎樣可以改正？
"You put supari (spice) in your mouth"
你放一點香料在口裡
Then "How much?"
放多少？
"It depends on the size of your mouth"
要看你的嘴巴有多大
"You don't know it even then how come you talk aobut Sahaja Yoga"
連放多少香料進嘴巴你也不知道 你怎能談霎哈嘉瑜伽
you don't know it even
即使這樣你也不知道
People like giving lecture
人們喜歡演講
Get on a stage and won't leave a mic
走到台上，不願意離開擴音器
Once with mic they cant't leave It's a new disease
一旦拿到擴音器，他們就是不走 這是一種新疾病
So you must understand why to give lecture
所以你們要明白，為什麽要演講
There are so many Mother's talk you can put a tape or video in every program
母親已經有很多講話 在每個講座裡，你們可以 播放母親的錄像帶或錄音帶
After people can write question on paper And ask them to bring it next program
之後他們可以寫下任何的問題 叫他們下次把問題帶來
If there are someone who is sick or in trouble
若某人病了或有麻煩
Now there is a Yogi He comes to cure in Calcutta
有個瑜伽士 他來加爾各答為人治病
Now he was called to Russia
他現在被召去俄羅斯
One person is running like Hanuman all over to cure
他像哈奴曼那樣四處去醫治人
You all can cure All women can do
你們也能醫治人 女人也可以
All men also But nobody tries
男人也可以 但卻沒有人嘗試這樣做
By giving lecture how many were cured?
透過演講，有多少人得到醫治？
don't know what's the matter that till now there is only one man in India who can cure people
不知道出什麽問題 直至現在，在印度 只有一個人能醫治人
In London there are 15~20 people who can cure and in France also
在倫敦，有約十五至二十人 能醫治人，法國也是
One should learn working on people like giving bandhan
你們要學習什麽方法醫治人 像做班丹…
No need to invite someone from abroad Remove Sahaja Yoga badges if you cannot cure
不需要邀請國外的人 若你不能醫治人 把霎哈嘉瑜伽的標籤除去吧
How do you work on others if you can't cure even yourself
若你連自己也治不好 又怎能治好別人
Everybody has got all the power to cure anyone
每個人都有能力醫治人
Learn to become masters
學習成為導師
Instead of inviting someone They should go out to cure
而不是請別人來做 他們要走出去醫治人
Just have some courage to work Nothing will happen
只要有勇氣做這份工作 沒什麽會發生在你身上
By working, you become deeper like a tree grows deeper as it expands
透過這份工作，你變得更深入 就像樹木擴展，它生長得更深
Sahaja Yogis are very much different from Incarnations
霎哈嘉瑜伽士 和降世神祇有很大分別
They have never worked in society before
他們從未在社會工作過
Nobody had the power for a mass
沒有人曾經擁有這麽多力量
Only one to one Like King Janaka to Nachiketa
只是一個給一個 就如Janak王給Nachiketa
But now you all have it Just grow it, that's all
但現在你們全都有力量 你只要成長，就這樣
Cure yourself and others Understand Sahaja Yoga, you have everything
醫治自己，醫治別人 你明白霎哈嘉瑜伽，你擁有一切
But still your attention is wondering What are you running after?
但你的注意力仍散亂在四處 不知道自己在追尋什麽
You still don't understand it Sahaja Yoga is just blessing
仍不明白 霎哈嘉瑜伽只是福佑
You won't be in short of anything
你不會缺乏什麽
Just work for sahaja Yoga Even if you don't work you will be blessed
只要為霎哈嘉瑜伽做事 即使什麽也不做，你也會受祝福
Business or promotion, this and that
生意擴展了，得到晉升
Everyone is blessed and nothing to give up
每個人都受到祝福 不需要放棄什麽
Otherwise in time of freedom fight
我們為自由抗爭的時候
we were tortured Lied on ice, got electric shocks
曾經被折磨 躺在冰塊上，被電擊
My parents went to jail Our house was sold
我父母進過多次監獄 我們的房子被出售
Lived in a hut... had to sacrifice a lot And you don't have to do it
我們要住在小屋裡，要犧牲很多 你們卻不用任何犧性
But not only recieving You have to give
你只是接受，但你也要付出
If one door is open so should be the other one Only one doesn't work
若一扇門打開，另一扇門也要打開 只開一扇門是不能成事
Everyone reports me about blessings they got
每個人都向我報告 他們有什麽福佑
We must see what we have done for others
我們要看看自己為別人做了什麽
But there are many fights for leadership It's all mother's play
很多人為想做領袖而爭鬥 這全是母親的戲劇
You will know it when you will fall from there
當你從那裡趺下 你就會知道
Specially women shouldn't get involved They fall very soon
特別是女人，不要牽涉入內 很快她們也會跌下
And men should know there is nothing like ministers
男人要知道 沒什麽像總理
This is Mother's play Don't get involved in
這是母親的戲劇 不要牽涉入內
Why I call a leader? It's a play There are no leaders
為何我稱呼領袖？只是一場戲 沒有誰是領袖
It's just a test if you have ego If you have, you are gone
只是考驗，若你有自我 若你有自我，你就會走
It will be shown immediately In Sahaja Yoga everything gets exposed
立即會顯露出來 在霎哈嘉瑜伽，一切都會被揭露
Even if I say something it shows on the faces
即使我說了什麽 也會在臉上表現出來
Once some leaders came and confessed their mistakes
有次有些領袖來 向我承認做錯事
They have more responsibilities to be better, sweet, humble and loving
領袖肩負更多責任 要更好，更甜、更謙卑，更有愛心
and become close and sharing with everyone
與每個人融合，與每個人分享
Now on the auspicious occasion of Shri Rama we must understand what he had showen
在羅摩這個吉祥的日子 我們要明白祂的生命 向我們展示了什麽
Only a bit of it would please our Mother
即使我們只能做到一點點 都能取悅母親
He was in exile for a long time in Jungle Walked barefeet, worked so hard
祂長時間被放逐到森林裡 赤腳行走，很辛勤的工作
Just to obey his father
只為遵從祂的父親
Now to obey me you don't need to go into exile
現在，要遵從我 你不用離鄉背井
Not barefeet, nor starving nothing All are there for you
不用赤腳走路，亦不用捱餓 一切都為你準備好
But you must know how to cure people in Sahaja Yoga
但在霎哈嘉瑜伽 你要知道怎樣醫治人
everything about sahaj yoga
要知道霎哈嘉瑜伽的一切
and mostly about love
而最重要要知道的是愛
it's nothing but power of love Everybody will be benefited
只是愛的力量 藉此每個人都得益
This is not only for special people
這不只是為特別的人而設
This is not only for one country but for the whole world
亦不只是為一個國家. 而是為全世界而設
Watch how your attention is If it's disturbed we should correct it
看看你的注意力放在哪裡 若注意力受騷擾，我們要糾正它
Put the power of spirit in it Do everything with concentration
把靈的力量放在注意力裡 做任何事都要集中精神
And devotion and love will make you deep
虔敬和愛會令你有深度
Otherwise there is lots of rubbish
不然，會有很多圾垃
If you wish to stay like rubbish you know where it goes at the end
若你想像圾垃 你也知道圾垃最終會怎樣
If you want to feel you are specially good capable of anything
若你以為自己很特別 能做任何事情
First humility, not only towards me but everyone
首先要謙卑，不是只對我 而是對每一個人
Talk humbly with love and show that people can blossom like lotus in Sahaja Yoga
以愛謙卑的說話，向人顯示 在霎哈嘉瑜伽，人可以像蓮花般盛放
to spread fragrance everywhere
他們的芬芳傳播四周
People will tell me you are wonderful if you will do it in that way
若你這樣做 人們會告訴我︰你很令人讚嘆
One day you too will be called as Maryada Purushottama
有天你們也會被稱為 maryada purushottam
You are the temple of Rama so have it within yourself
你是羅摩的廟宇，因此你要有它在內
Perform puja to it Take care of your self-esteem
向它做崇拜，好好照顧你的自尊
Take the benefit of self-realization inside yourself
在你內在取得自覺的好處
You must have respect and devotion to it
你必須對它尊重和虔敬
"Now we are realized" "How can we do wrong, we are yogi"
我們現在已有自覺 我們怎能做錯事，我們是瑜伽士
Soon you will have blessings immediately
很快你會擁有很多福佑 立即
As I am called Rokra devi, you will get blessing as soon as you assert it
就如我被稱為 Rokra devi 一旦你維護它，你會得到福佑
Everyone is getting blessed with it give it back to the world
每個人都受它的祝福 再回報給全世界
Shri Rama used all his powers for the benevolence of people to show the ideal
就如羅摩把祂所有力量用在 人民的福祉上，展示祂為榜樣典範
You will be surprised to achieve so high when the time comes
你會很驚訝，當時候到了 你們都有很高的成就
You won't have any disease and all bad habits will be dropped
你不會有任何疾病 所有壞習慣亦會戒掉
You will eat, talk and watch as much as you need
你需要時才吃，需要時才說話 需要時才看
You will watch your mind for introspection
你會因內省而觀察自己的思維
"Where is my mind going?" "I'm a Sahaja Yogi, stop it"
我在想什麽？ 我是霎哈嘉瑜伽士，停止這樣吧
By doing so you will be in meditation
透過這樣做，你會在入靜中
Your kundalini will be satisfied and give you blessings
你的靈量亦會很滿足 並賜予你祝福
You say, "Mother what a blessing"
那麽你就會說 母親，這是何等的福佑
But you have to jump into it Only then will you know it
但你要跳進去 只有這樣你才會知道
Till then you need to work hard
直到那時候，你還需要辛勤工作
Shri Rama was born at midnight so let's have puja late
羅摩是在午夜出生 所以讓我們遲一點才開始崇拜
Shri Rama Puja is not a specially long one
羅摩的崇拜也不特別長
As he is in a human form he is humanity within us
因為祂是以人類的形相 祂是我們內在的人性
by which we understand our intellect and our thoughts get changed
藉此我們明白知性 我們的思維亦得到改變
Shri Rama is that Through him we can change our thoughts
羅摩就是這樣 透過羅摩，我們改變我們的想法
Our nature can change Because he is our ideal
亦改變了我們的本質 因為祂是我們的榜樣典範
After achieving his ideals we reach another because he was human ideal
當我們到達祂的典範，我們就能到 其他典範，因為祂是人類的典範
It is great that God came to this world in a human form to became our ideal
神以人的形相來到這個世界 是很了不起的 祂成為我們的典範
He has gone through all the hardships to show us strength to keep Dharma
祂經歷所有困難 向我們顯示要有力量持守正法
That is Vishwa Dharma and the state of yoga
即普世無沾的正法 和瑜伽的狀態
May God bless you all
願神祝福你們